Danny Kaye and Sylvia Fine Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Photographs, 1918-1991 (Box 428-430, 435-438, 502-532, 538-541, 622, 625, 627-628, 638-640, 766, 768-769, 787, 791, Mapcase folder 2)
  - Albums, 1939-1986
    - Events – Plant Tour/Mercedes Benz, 1971 (Box-folder 540/3)
    - Fan-Created Album – Danny Kaye in Denmark, 1952-1986 (Box-folder 541/3)
    - Fan-Created Album – Danny Kaye Show, 1965 (Box-folder 541/2)
    - Fan-Created Album – London, 1949-1952, Created by Margot Whitworth. Candid shots of Kaye and fans. (Box-folder 541/4)
    - Fan-Created Album – London, undated (Box-folder 541/5-6)
    - Glasgow/Compliments of Sir Alex B. King, 1949, June 5-12 (Box-folder 766/1)
    - Glasgow, 1949, June 5-12, Includes Kaye on stage, golfing, meeting with Harry Lauder, and in parades. (Box-folder 627/1)
    - Hobbies – Aviation DC 10 Friendship 72 World Tour, 1971 (Box-folder 538/2)
    - Public Service
      - Israel, 1956 (Box-folder 605/1)
      - Israel/Navy, 1967 (Box-folder 430/1)
      - Moscow, 1963 (Box-folder 605/2)
      - UNICEF, 1971 (Box-folder 538/1)
      - UNICEF/Israel, 1959 (Box-folder 429/2)
      - UNICEF/Japan, 1954 (Box-folder 539/3)
      - United Nations Command, 1961, December 22-30 (Box-folder 539/5)
      - United States Air Force, 1945-1966, Created by Major Ben I. Funk. (Box-folder 539/1)
      - United States Army Hospital/Okinawa, 1967 (Box-folder 428/2)
      - United States Navy/USS Enterprise, 1966, April (Box-folder 539/2)
      - USO/Kuma Station, Japan, 1962, January 2 (Box-folder 539/4)
    - Stage – Manchester, 1949 (Box-folder 429/1)
    - Stage – Philadelphia, 1954 (Box-folder 540/1)
    - Stage – South African Tour, 1954 (Box-folder 602/1)
    - Stage – Lake Tahoe/Harrah's, undated (Box-folder 540/2)
    - Sylvia and Danny, 1940s-1950s, Includes publicity photographs of Kaye and Fine; Pabst radio; Command Performance radio show rehearsals; Floradora girls rehearsal and performance with Groucho Marx, Edward G. Robinson, Phil Silvers, Gene Kelly; Katherine Hepburn and Sam Goldwyn; F.A.B Show with Leo Durocher; and March of Dimes with Groucho Marx and Jimmy Durante. (Box-folder 628/1)
    - University of South Carolina/Honorary Degree, undated (Box-folder 603/1)
- Scrapbooks, 1939-1981 (Box 431-434, 542, 602-621, 629-630, 632-633, 767, 770, 791)
  Bound volumes created by Kaye/Fine staff or given to Kaye documenting his travels and performances. Includes clippings, photographs, and memorabilia.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Straw Hat Review, 1939 see also Straw Hat Review for printed program (Box-folder 431/1)
  - Kaye, Danny Clippings from Lincoln Center Files, 1939-1963 (Box-folder 542/1-2)
  - Let's Face It, 1941 (Box-folder 791/11)
  - Danny Kaye, 1941-1947 (Box-folder 606/1)
  - Cleveland Press Christmas Show, 1946 (Box-folder 620/1)
  - Clippings of Danny Kaye's Visit to Israel, 1946, April (Box-folder 542/3)
  - Detroit's Red Feather Show Starring Danny Kaye, 1946, November 12 (Box-folder 633/1)
  - Danny Kaye in London, 1948 (Box-folder 620/2)
  - Danny Kaye in London, Parts I and II, 1949 (Box-folder 621/1, 607/2)
  - Danny Kaye in Manchester, Birmingham, Liverpool, 1949 (Box-folder 607/1)
  - Glasgow/Press Cuttings, 1949, June 5-12 (Box-folder 629/1)
  - Glasgow/Press Cuttings/Compliments of Alex B. King, 1949, June 5-12 (Box-folder 767/2)
  - Glasgow, 1950 (Box-folder 619/2)
  - Danny Kaye, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 608/1)
  - Danny Kaye in England, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 432/1)
  - Danny Kaye in England, 1951 (Box-folder 431/2)
  - Danny Kaye, 1952 (Box-folder 609/1)
  - Danny Kaye at New York Palace, 1953 (Box-folder 608/2)
  - Africa and World Tour, 1954 (Box-folder 434/3)
  - Danny Kaye in Bombay, 1954 (Box-folder 432/2)
  - UNICEF/Hong Kong, 1954 (Box-folder 767/1)
  - Knock on Wood, 1954 (Box-folder 619/3)
  - Knock on Wood Launching Campaign/Paris, 1954, October (Box-folder 633/2)
  - Danny Kaye/Philadelphia, 1954 (Box-folder 434/1)
  - Philadelphia, 1954 (Box-folder 612/1)
  - Kaye Day in Cleveland, 1955, November 12 (Box-folder 434/2)
  - Knock on Wood/Barcelona and Madrid, 1955 (Box-folder 770/1-2)
  - UNICEF/Holland, 1955, October, 5-8 (Box-folder 618/1-2)
  - Variety Club Luncheon/London, 1955 (Box-folder 616/1)
  - Australian Weekly/Sydney, 1959, May-July (Box-folder 632/3)
  - Danny Kaye and His International All-Stars/Empire Theatre/Sydney, Australia, 1959 (Box-folder 542/4-5)
  - Danny Kaye and His International All-Stars/Melbourne/Princess Theatre, 1959 (Box-folder 632/1)
  - The Five Pennies/Thailand, 1959 (Box-folder 619/4)
  - Sydney, 1959 (Box-folder 632/2)
  - An Hour with Danny Kaye, 1960 (Box-folder 433/2)
  - Danny Kaye Special, 1961, November 6 (Box-folder 610/1, 611/1)
  - Danny Kaye/Ziegfeld Theatre, 1963, April 10 (Box-folder 612/2)
  - United States Information Agency/Journey to Moscow, 1963, July, Includes correspondence with Edward R. Murrow and George Stevens, Jr. (Box-folder 617/2)
  - Danny Kaye for UNICEF, 1965 (Box-folder 616/2)
  - UNICEF/Norway, 1965 (Box-folder 615/1)
  - Danny Kaye Tour with Israel Youth Orchestra, 1967 (Box-folder 630/1)
  - Gadna in Buenos Aires, Argentina, 1967 (Box-folder 434/4)
  - Gadna Tour, 1967, October-November (Box-folder 613/1, 614/1)
  - UNICEF/Visit of Danny Kaye, Paul Edwards/Manila, 1971, March (Box-folder 619/1)
  - New York Philharmonic Benefit Concert, 1981, September 23 (Box-folder 617/1)
  - Skokie, 1981 (Box-folder 615/2)
  - Danny Kaye, undated, Created by Jerry Horlock. (Box-folder 542/6)
  - Pictures of the Danny Kaye Show, undated (Box-folder 433/1)
- Clippings, 1940-1989 (Box 592-595, 440, 768)
  Clippings files maintained by Kaye/Fine staff. Additional clippings are found throughout the collection.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject, then chronologically or alphabetically therein as appropriate.
  - Awards, 1957-1986 (Box-folder 592/1-3)
  - Biographical, 1954, 1959, 1961, 1987, Includes Danny Kaye obituaries. (Box-folder 592/4-7)
  - Concerts, 1963-1981 (Box-folder 592/8-9)
  - Events, 1960-1969, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 592/10-20)
  - Films – The Court Jester, 1956 (Box-folder 592/21-22, 440/6)
  - Films – The Five Pennies, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 592/23-29)
  - Films – H-W, 1945-1968 (Box-folder 592/30-34, 593/1-8)
  - Hobbies, 1962-1977 (Box-folder 593/9-12, 768/12)
  - Miscellaneous, 1940-1986, undated (Box-folder 593/13-26, 594/1-15, 440/7)
  - Recordings, 1955-1958, 1966 (Box-folder 594/16)
  - Stage, 1949-1969 (Box-folder 594/17-33)
  - Television, 1960-1967, 1975, 1981, 1985 (Box-folder 594/34-40, 595/1-2)
  - Theatrical Productions, 1941, 1967, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 595/3-5)
  - UNICEF, 1954-1983 (Box-folder 595/6-21)
  - USO, 1961-1967 (Box-folder 595/22)
  - Fine, Sylvia, 1954-1989 (Box-folder 595/23)
  - Kaye, Dena, 1959, 1961-1985 (Box-folder 595/24)
- Iconography, 1940s-1980s (Box 440, 532, 624, 636, 768, Mapcase folder 1)
  Original artwork depicting Danny Kaye performing or in portrait. Includes caricatures, cartoons, drawings, and paintings. There is also a small group of drawings by children.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of depicition and alphabetically by artist.
  - Kaye, Danny
    - Cartoons/Caricatures – Antonio, 1966 (Box-folder 636/4)
    - Cartoons/Caricatures – Clippings, 1954-1968 (Box-folder 624/7)
    - Cartoons/Caricatures – Miscellaneous, 1941, 1962-1967, 1971, undated, Contains original drawings and copies, and an animation cel for an unknown project; Includes works by Jim Berry, David Folkman, Al Hirschfeld, and Jim Lange. (Box-folder 532/3, 636/3, 768/13)
    - Cartoons/Caricatures – Punch, 1957 (Box-folder 624/8)
    - Cartoons/Caricatures – Rafty, Tony, 1975 (Box-folder 769/11)
    - Drawings – Baker, Ernest Hamlin, 1946, Original Time magazine cover (Box-folder 636/5)
    - Drawings – Bates, Bill, 1965, Original (Box-folder 624/9)
    - Drawings – Davis, Jack, undated (Box-folder 624/10)
    - Drawings – Kingman, Dong, 1959, March, Original drawings and photographic negatives; On Five Pennies set. (Box-folder 624/11)
    - Drawings – Lesset, Ron, undated, Original and photographic prints (Box-folder 624/12)
    - Drawings – Miscellaneous, 1959, 1962, 1969, undated, Contains original drawings and copies including a set of crayon drawings done by children; Artists include R. R. Bombé, Bruce Duykers, George Lonn, Ben Shenkman, and Bernard Windsor. (Box-folder 532/4, 440/10-11, 768/14)
    - Drawings – Nielsen, undated, Original crayon on velvet (Box-folder 624/13)
    - Magazine Covers, 1946, 1963 (Box-folder 624/14)
    - Painting - Taxin, John, undated (Mapcase folder 1)
  - Kaye, Dena – Caricature, 1956 (Box-folder 440/15)
- Honors, 1945-1987 (Box 441, 624, 637, 596-601, 776-780, 782-786, 789, 794)
  Awards, certificates and honorary degree diplomas, medals, plaques, and trophies presented to Danny Kaye and Sylvia Fine. The bulk of the materials were presented to Kaye.
  Arranged alphabetically by file unit: Awards, Certificates, Honorary Degree Diplomas, Medals, Plaques, and Trophies. Each file unit is also arranged alphabetically by presenting entity or honor title.
  - Awards
    - Actor's Fund of America, 1971, April 22 (Box-folder 596/1)
    - American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations/Murray Green Award, 1978 (Box-folder 596/2)
    - American Friends of Hebrew University/Scopus Award, 1977, May 18, Includes phonograph record. (Box-folder 779/2)
    - American Theatre Wing/Antoinette Perry Award, 1953 (Box-folder 599/1)
    - Ben-Gurion University of Negev, 1976 (Box-folder 596/3)
    - Ben-Gurion University of the Negev Lifetime Achievement Award, 1982, January 26, Middle Canaanite I period clay pot (Box 785)
    - Boys' Towns of Italy/World of Entertainment Award, 1974, March 28 (Box-folder 776/1)
    - Brooklyn College Alumni Association/Alumni of the Year/Sylvia Fine Kaye, 1958 (Box-folder 601/13)
    - Brooklyn College Alumni Association/Los Angeles Southern California Chapter/Distinguished Alumni Award/Sylvia Fine Kaye, 1983, March 27 (Box-folder 598/7)
    - Children's Theatre Conference Monte Meacham Award, 1959, Inscribed silver martini pitcher with stirrer (Box-folder 780/1)
    - Deauville American Film Festival/Danny Kaye Award, 1980 (Box-folder 600/7)
    - Eastern New York Jr. High School Hall of Fame, 1949 (Box-folder 794/3)
    - Film Advisory Board/Award of Excellence/Musical Comedy Tonight, 1979, October (Box-folder 598/4)
    - General Maurice Rose Memorial Medal/Humanitarian Service, 1946 (Box-folder 601/7)
    - Grand Order of the Water Rats, 1974 (Box-folder 599/10)
    - Hadassah/Beverly Hills Chapter/Woman of Achievement Award/Sylvia Fine Kaye, 1983, November 19 (Box-folder 776/4)
    - Haganah Day of Valor Plaque/to Danny Kaye, 1967, July 4 (Box-folder 601/16)
    - International Center for the Disabled/Special Recognition Award, 1982 (Box-folder 596/4)
    - Israel/Prime Minister's Award, 1968, 1973 (Box-folder 596/5, 598/3, 599/2)
    - Israel/Silver Anniversary Cultural Medal, 1973, June 3, Decorative element depicts the Twelve Tribes of Israel (Box 789)
    - Joint Defense Appeal of the American Jewish Committee Anti-Defamation League/Motion Picture Division/Human Relations Award, 1955 (Box-folder 596/6)
    - John F. Kennedy Center/Honor, 1984, December 2 (Box-folder 777/1)
    - Le Soir, 1955, September 30 (Box-folder 596/7)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews/Brotherhood Award, 1953, February 19 (Box-folder 601/8)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews/Mass Media Award, 1966 (Box-folder 596/ 8)
    - Parents' Magazine Medal, 1955, 1959 (Box-folder 596/9)
    - People of Israel, 1974, February 11, Middle Bronze age clay pot; Given for support during the Yom Kippur War. (Box 786)
    - Schubert Foundation Award, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 596/10)
    - Schlesinger Organisation Award of Merit, 1954, Bronze African drummer sculpture (Box-folder 780/3)
    - Screen Actors Guild Annual Award, 1982 (Box-folder 780/2)
    - State of Israel Bonds/Eleanor Roosevelt Humanities Award, 1969 (Box-folder 596/11)
    - Thomas Jefferson High School/Alumni Association/Distinguished Alumni Award/Sylvia Fine Kaye, 1963, May 3 (Box-folder 776/2)
    - UNICEF/International Year of Children, 1979, June 23 (Box-folder 596/12)
    - University of Georgia/George Foster Peabody Broadcasting Award/Secret Life of Danny Kaye, 1956 (Box-folder 596/13)
    - University of Georgia/George Foster Peabody Broadcasting Award/Danny Kaye Show, 1963 (Box-folder 596/14)
    - University of Georgia/George Foster Peabody Broadcasting Award/Musical Comedy Tonight, 1979 (Box-folder 596/15)
    - University of Georgia/George Foster Peabody Broadcasting Award/Live at Lincoln Center and Skokie, 1981 (Box-folder 596/16)
    - USO/New York City Committee/Distinguished Service Award, 1983 (Box-folder 596/17)
    - Utah State University/Robins Award of America, undated (Box-folder 596/18)
    - Ville De Paris, 1966 (Box-folder 596/19)
    - Yale School of Music/Sanford Fellowship, 1976, April 24 (Box-folder 596/20)
  - Certificates, A complete, alphabetical list of all of Kaye's certificates is located in Box 441/2.
    - Fine, Sylvia, 1953, 1959, 1983 (Box-folder 441/1, 769/12)
    - Kaye, Danny, "A-Z" Miscellaneous, 1945-1985 (Box-folder 441/2-9, 442/1-10, 637/1-6, 769/13)
  - Honorary Degrees
    - Kaye, Danny, Miscellaneous, 1955, 1972, 1978, 1980, 1985, 1987 (Box-folder 624/15, 769/14)
  - Medals
    - American College of Cardiology/Convocation Medal, 1981, March 18 (Box-folder 598/6)
    - Armed Forces Operation Entertainment, undated (Box-folder 596/21)
    - Denmark/Danmark's Turistrad, undated (Box-folder 596/22)
    - Boston Symphony Orchestra Medal, undated (Box-folder 596/23)
    - Denmark/Order of Dannebrog, undated (Box-folder 596/24)
    - France/Legion of Honor, undated (Box-folder 596/25)
    - France/Ordre des Artes et des Lettres, undated (Box-folder 596/26)
    - Hunter College/President's Medal, undated (Box-folder 596/27)
    - Israel/Jabotinsky Medal, undated (Box-folder 596/28)
    - National Institute of Social Sciences/Gold Medal, 1966 (Box-folder 596/29)
    - President of The United States of America/Medal of Freedom, 1987 (Box-folder 599/3)
    - Tutzinger Stern, undated (Box-folder 596/30)
  - Plaques
    - General Rose Memorial Hospital/Children's Division Dedication, 1961, December 2 (Box-folder 600/5)
    - South African Tour/African Consolidated Theatres, 1954, May (Box-folder 779/1)
    - Town and Gown/University of Southern California/Sylvia Fine Kaye Scholarship, 1986, February 25 (Box-folder 598/5)
    - University of Southern California/Division of Drama/Outstanding Achievement/Sylvia Fine Kaye, 1985, November (Box-folder 776/3)
    - U. S. Naval Forces Marianas - Crossroads of the Pacific, 1967, August (Box-folder 600/3)
  - Trophies
    - American Legion Auxiliary/Golden Mike Award/Best Variety Show, 1964 (Box-folder 601/11)
    - Boy Scouts of Brooklyn, undated (Box-folder 600/1)
    - Brookhaven Country Club, Dallas, Tex., Service City Invitational and National Aviation Golf Championship, Flying Entertainer of the Year, 1966, May 23 (Box 782)
    - Civic Unity Council and B'nai Brith, Vancouver, British Columbia, 1952, November 11, Totem pole (Box 783)
    - Hollywood Foreign Correspondents Association/Golden Globe/Me and the Colonel, 1959 (Box-folder 601/9)
    - Hollywood Foreign Correspondents Association/Golden Globe/On the Riviera, 1951 (Box-folder 601/10)
    - Los Angeles Dodgers Danny Goodman Award, 1985, August 10 (Box 784)
    - National Academy of Television Arts and Sciences/Emmy Award/Producer Look In at the Met, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 597/1)
    - National Academy of Television Arts and Sciences/Emmy Award/Best Performance in a Variety Show, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 597/2)
    - The Paramount Men/Sylvia Kaye The Champion Hostess, 1954 (Box-folder 598/1)
    - Screen Guide Award/Best Performance by a Comedian/Wonder Man, 1946 (Box-folder 601/12)
    - United Nations/Distinguished Service, 1977 (Box-folder 600/2)
- Realia, 1949-1984 (Box 596, 599-601, 778, 780-781, 788, 790, CPL, INSTR)
  Memorabilia and presentation items given to or saved by Danny Kaye.
  Arranged alphabetically by item type or presenting organization.
  - Abruzza/Cigarette Case, 1978, September, Inscribed "25 anni con L'UNICEF" and "sempre piu mi piace questo Jacobowski." (Box-folder 596/31)
  - Abruzza Medallion, undated, Inscribed "sempre piu mi piace questo Jacobowski." (Box-folder 601/2)
  - Batons
    - Gadna Orchestra/International Tour, 1967 (Box-folder 778/3)
    - Golden Flyswatter/Syracuse Symphony, 1979, March 31 (Box-folder 778/2)
    - Inscribed to Danny Kaye from Jo Lombardi, undated (Box-folder 778/1)
    - Inscribed to Danny Kaye from the Boston Symphony Orchestra, 1957, April (Box-folder 778/4)
    - Katims, Milton and Seattle Symphony Women's Association, 1975, 3 pieces; Toscanini baton from Katims' personal collection, baton in plexiglass tube inserted in stand. (Box-folder 778/6)
    - Variety Club of Great Britain/Manchester Committee, 1974, May, 2 pieces; brass baton, green agate stand (Box-folder 778/5)
  - Brooklyn Police Badge, undated (Box-folder 596/32)
  - Canadian National Exhibition/Mementos, 1958 (Box-folder 599/8)
  - City of New York/Presented by Robert F. Wagner, 1963, April 7 (Box-folder 596/33)
  - Clapboard (Polavision), 1978 (Box-folder 600/4)
  - Confrére de la Chaine de Rotisseurs, undated (Box-folder 596/34)
  - Copenhagen/Seal, undated (Box-folder 596/35)
  - Cornet in B-flat, 1950s, Selmer et Cie, Paris, serial number 1455; Note: Used by Danny Kaye in his role as cornetist Red Nichols in The Five Pennies
  - Far East Command/Lighter Case, 1951, Inscribed to Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 601/5)
  - Flying Fickle Finger of Fate, undated (Box-folder 600/8)
  - Israeli Bayonet, undated, Scabbard inscribed "To Yacobovski from an immigrant colonel." (Box-folder 599/6)
  - Izod Bucket Hat, undated (Box-folder 780/4)
  - Israeli Defense Forces/Flight Training School, 1976, April (Box-folder 601/15)
  - Jerusalem Theatre/Special Benefit Performance Coin, 1976, May 4 (Box-folder 601/14)
  - Kaye, Danny – Bust, undated, Bronze mounted on wood; By Rhonda Stern.
  - Kaye, Danny – Hands, undated, Bronze mounted on wood
  - London Palladium/Inscribed Loving Cup, 1951 (Box-folder 599/9)
  - Membership Cards, 1950, 1959, 1979, American Federation of Musicians, Saints and Sinners, U. S. Treasury War Bonds Vounteer, and Variety Club Toronto. (Box-folder 601/3)
  - Military Patches, undated (Box-folder 601/1)
  - Pasadena Tournament of Roses/Grand Marshal Ribbon, 1984, January 2 (Box-folder 599/4)
  - Pins and Buttons, 1970, undated, IV Corps pin, Expo '70 buttons, Scottish balmoral pin, troy ounce silver. (Box-folder 601/4)
  - Pittsburgh/Honorary Police Badge, undated (Box-folder 596/36)
  - San Antonio Symphony presentation box, 1978, Display case for To learn to sing, observe these rules (1755), which has been removed and cataloged as 2018560681; Includes magnifying glass and book cover (Box 790)
  - Silver Goblet, 1952, Inscribed "to Danny Kaye happy memories of your visit to Cardiff Wales - June 30 1952 - with affection from Nossie Sherman." (Box-folder 600/9)
  - Score/Rossini Ouvertur zur Oper, Die diebische Elster, 1966, Inscribed to Danny Kaye by London Philharmonic members. (Box-folder 600/10)
  - Score/Rossini La Gazza Ladra, undated, Inscribed to Danny Kaye by New York Philharmonic members. (Box-folder 600/11)
  - Shillelagh, 1949, June, In leather case; From Harry Lauder. (Box 781)
  - UNICEF Mementos, 1971, undated, 3 items (Box-folder 601/6-7)
  - United States Army 1st Cavalry Division Helmet, undated, Personalized "Danny Kaye." (Box-folder 599/7)
  - Variety Club of Great Britian, 1975, Musical notes mounted on green agate (Box-folder 600/6)
  - White Crusaders Boys' Movement of Great Britain Danny Kaye Jigsaw Puzzle, 1975 (Box 788)
- Appendix A: Kaye/Fine Book Inventory
  The Kaye/Fine Book Inventory provides a list of books donated as part of the Danny Kaye and Sylvia Fine Collection.